

# ISRAEL MEDINA

medinaisrael\_17@yahoo.com | 512-905-3426 | Round Rock, TX 78665

#### Summary

Certified Full Stack Developer. Experienced in creating user-centric products for both desktop and mobile platforms. Talented in working in HTML, JavaScript, and React.js. Bringing a strong work ethic and excellent organizational skills to any setting. Excited to begin a new challenge with a successful team.

#### Skills

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Node, MySQL, MongoDB
- Sequelize, Mongoose.js
- Handlebars, React
- Progressive Web Apps (PWA)
- Experience with version repository Problem Resolution
- Application development
- Interface design and implementation
- Customer-oriented

- Proficient in HTML
- Can use Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator
- Relationship Development
- Customer Service
- One-on-one and small group instruction
- Leadership
- Socially Apt
- Requirements analysis and design phases

## Experience

#### **Teacher Assistant**

08/2019 - Current

2U Inc. / The University of Texas at Austin | Austin, TX

- Assisted instructors in monitoring students' progress and by reviewing test scores and classwork.
- Drove social, emotional, intellectual, and physical development through age-appropriate enrichment activities.
- Contributed to a positive, educational setting by delivering gentle discipline and promoting student success.
- Tutored and supported students individually and in groups of up to five by reteaching and reviewing lesson concepts and ensuring their understanding of the current unit.
- Graded assignments and tests using an answer key, documented results and informed lead teacher of students' performance.
- Helped students master learning concepts through one-on-one and small group tutoring.

 Wrote guides and found extra resources to help students learn complicated topics such as JavaScript, ORM's, React, etc.

#### **Assistant Manager**

06/2017 - 12/2017

CUTCO | Cedar Park, TX

- Mentored staff to enhance skills and achieve daily targets, using hands-on and motivational leadership.
- Coached and mentored employees by delivering training, guidance and performance monitoring.
- Maintained a positive work ethic and commitment to providing excellent service to improve operations efficiency and customer satisfaction.
- Evaluated employee performance and developed improvement plans.
- Collaborated with office managers to develop strategies for achieving sales and profit goals.
- Conducted job interviews, led employee performance evaluations with constructive feedback.

**Sales Associate** 01/2018 - 01/2019

J. Crew | Round Rock, TX

- Arranged new merchandise with signage and appealing displays to encourage customer sales and move overstock items.
- Retained product, service and company policy knowledge to serve as a resource for both coworkers and customers.
- Answered incoming telephone calls to provide information about products, services, store hours, policies and promotions.
- Sold various products by explaining unique features and educating customers on proper application.
- Assisted customers by finding needed clothing items and checking inventory for items at other locations.
- Processed orders through system and coordinated product deliveries.
- Built and maintained effective relationships with peers and upper management to drive team success toward common sales, service and operational goals.
- Won store sales competition for the store credit card, resulting in recognition and bonuses.
- Met or exceeded upselling, donation and credit card sign-up targets on a consistent basis by leveraging excellent communication and interpersonal strengths.
- Used register system to ring up customer purchases, process payments, and issue receipts.
- Designed and deployed new display ideas to improve accessibility to merchandise.
- Readied merchandise for the sales floor by marking items with

identifying codes and accurate pricing.

- Unboxed new merchandise and restocked shelves in appealing and organized arrangements to promote items.
- Recommended optimal merchandise based on customer needs and desires.
- Stayed up to date on store promotions, payment policies and security practices.
- Communicated with customers about clothing offerings, including policies, restrictions and refund policies.

**Sales Associate** 08/2016 - 02/2017

Clarks Bostonian | Round Rock, TX

- Arranged new merchandise with signage and appealing displays to encourage customer sales and move overstock items.
- Maintained knowledge of current promotions, exchange guidelines, payment policies, and security practices.
- Stayed up to date on store promotions, payment policies and security practices.
- Recommended optimal merchandise based on customer needs and desires.
- Unboxed new merchandise and restocked shelves in appealing and organized arrangements to promote items.
- Performed floor moves, merchandising, display maintenance and housekeeping to keep sales areas well-stocked, organized and current.
- Educated customers on product and service offerings.
- Readied merchandise for the sales floor by marking items with identifying codes and accurate pricing.
- Demonstrated products to customers, discussed features and redirected objections to capture sales.
- Processed orders through system and coordinated product deliveries.

## Education and Training

Certification: Web Development

05/2019

University of Texas At Austin | Austin, TX

- Completed coursework in HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Learned back end software such as Node.js, MySQL, and MongoDB.
- Learned ORM such as Mongoose.js.
- Learned frameworks such as Handlebars, Laravel, and React.
- Received certification in Full Stack Development.

**Some College (No Degree)**: Computer Science And Programming Austin Community College | Austin, TX

### Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://israelmedina.dev
- https://github.com/medinaisrael-17
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/israel-medina-271344180/

## Activities and Honors

- National Honor Society (NHS)
- Madison Scouts Drum and Bugle Corps (2018, 2020)
- ACC Jazz Ensemble

### Additional Information

Thank you so much for taking the time to view my resume. I am a Full Stack Developer who loves music as much as my passion for design and software. I live in Round Rock but am willing to commute/relocate anywhere for the job. Open to challenges and new ideas, I will use my soft skills and knowledge to complete any task at hand. I look forward to meeting you.